AI is devastating white-collar careers.
A study by the Pew Research Center
showed that workers with higher
educational degrees are the most likely
to be replaced by AI.
>> So, AI may be coming for some job
sectors, but as far as plumbers and
electricians and those kinds of trade
jobs [music] go, uh those people are
safe.
>> The Office of Personnel Management is
launching a new initiative today called
the US Tech Force. They're going to work
alongside all government agencies and
several top technology companies
including Alphabet, Apple, IBM, Meta,
Microsoft, Nvidia, Open AI, and so many
more.
>> AI seems to be the answer for
everything.
>> Hello everybody. Here's a topic for us.
AI, artificial intelligence. AI is
changing white-collar work for some
people. That could mean losing a job.
That's alarming. Tens of thousands of
layoffs already happened in 2024 and
2025. Amazon announced about 14,000
corporate job cuts this year as it
increases its use of AI tools. Meta has
also cut around 600 jobs in its AI
division, and in October alone, Google
reportedly laid off more than 100
employees. Is AI a pro or a con? Is it a
friend or a foe? Who makes AI? We do. AI
won't replace you, but someone who knows
how to use AI might. Everything is
heading in that direction. Whether it's
banking, whether it's writing a simple
email, AI can do that for me now, and
I've used that one at work several
times. Need to challenge myself to dig
in a little deeper to AI. It's an
industrial revolution. Just like when
machines came out, they said these
machines are going to replace jobs, and
to a certain degree, they did in certain
sectors. But, they can't fully replace
the human brain. It's us who make AI. If
we can learn how to manage AI, I feel
like it might be all right. I'm really
curious to see what you guys think. Is
AI affecting you and how? Does it
concern you and why? Feel free to chime
in anytime. We really appreciate your
comments. I hope everybody has a great
day or a great night, wherever in the
world you are.